Preliminary Inventory to the Open End (Television Program) Sound Recordings, 1960-1961
Hoover Institution Archives
Open End (Television Program) sound recordings,
1960-1961
79103
Open end (Television program)
5 cubic foot boxes (5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Phonotape reels of interviews with Premier Nikita Khrushchev of the Soviet Union, Vice President Richard M. Nixon of the U.S., Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller of New York, and others, relating to Soviet-American relations, American politics, the election of 1960, and other subjects. Interviews conducted by David Susskind.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1979
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Presidents--United States--Election--1960.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; Phonotapes.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Susskind, David Howard, 1920-
Container List
- Sound recording of interview with Richard M. Nixon, 1960 May (Reel 1-8)
  Use copy reference number: 79103_a_0002625
  David Susskind interviews Vice President Nixon about foreign affairs, domestic affairs, and politics. In the first section, the men discuss a variety of topics. First is the U2 plane incident. Nixon believes America ought to conduct surveillance because the Soviet Union is not an open society; that the Soviet Union does not grant the diplomatic access America does to her. The men then consider if the actions of America put its allies in danger. Nixon points to the Paris conference, starting the following day, as an indication of where each country's policies are. Other topics of much discussion are on testing, disarmament--with Nixon again bring up the difficulty of running an open society and upholding an agreement with the Soviet Union--and nuclear proliferation. On communist China, Nixon believes there is tension between the Soviet Union and Mao. The discussion focuses on how China fits into nuclear proliferation, and why/when the United Nations should or should not admit communist China into the body. Nixon believes China violates the preamble clause of members being peaceful nations and that its admission would start the communization of the entire Southeast Asia area. On Latin America, Nixon believes anti-American sentiments have improved since his return from that region, saying there are far greater pro-American feelings than anti-American feelings. Indeed, he believes most people around the world prefer the American way over the communist way. The men cover a variety of topics on the domestic front as well. Beginning, Nixon defines what he means by progressive conservatism, arguing it is not a contradiction in terms. Nixon does not view safety-net programs, such as social security, as a welfare-state within the country--he believes government should offer services whenever the private sector does not want to, or cannot, provide those services. Meanwhile, he believes the private sector is more efficient than the federal government, qualifying with the private sector is not always absolutely efficient. On education, Nixon believes the federal government needs to step in, but only in certain ways, in order to ensure a high quality system. Regarding taxes, he says one cannot make any promises, because the economic future is never known. Nixon offers his thoughts on the Landrum Griffin Act and how organized labor should operate. He does not believe the civil rights movement should be viewed as a question of legality, but as a question of morality. Similarly, he analyzes the recent civil rights bill that Congress passed; he believes the bill would have been stronger were it not for Southern Democrats. Other topics include federalism, socialized medicine, the 1960 campaign, the late Senator McCarthy, foreign aid, and a bill to help areas in the Industrial Belt. Discussing politics, Susskind asks why the Republican Party is not the majority party, how Nixon intends to rally Democrats to him, the relationship of big business and the GOP, and what it takes to be President of the United States. Earlier in the program, Nixon states that he and Eisenhower share the same ideas on policy, and he hopes the era of selecting the vice president to balance the ticket is over.
- Duplicate of above (Reel 9-12)
- Sound recording of interview with Nikita Khrushchev 1960 October 16 (Reel 13-16)
- Duplicate of above (Reel 17-18)
- Sound recording of interview with Nelson A. Rockefeller 1960 June 12 (Reel 19-21)
- Duplicate of above (Reel 22)
- Sound recording of "Potpourri of Opinion," interviews with show business personalities 1960 July 27 (Reel 23-25)
  Use copy reference number: 79103_a_0002627
  Recorded after the Democratic Convention, this is a panel discussion focused on whether American society is in decline. Topics included are politicians/government; the arts; the younger generation, juvenile delinquency, and the Beatniks; marriage, the nuclear family, and gender roles. Panelists: Steve Allen, Pamela Mason, Dr. Frank Baxter, Shelley Winters, and Richard L. Breen, with David Susskind as moderator.
- Sound recording of "Voices of Africa" 1960 October 23 (Reel 26-29)
- Sound recording of "New Orleans Crisis," relating to desegregation 1960 December 18 (Reel 30-32)
  Use copy reference number: 79103_a_0002628
  This is a panel discussion on school desegregation in New Orleans. Panelists include (spelling may be incorrect): Leander Perez, Lloyd Rittner, Emile Wagner, Mary San, and John Nelson.
- Sound recording of "Look at the World by World Correspondents" 1961 January 15 (Reel 33-34)
- Sound recording of "Hollywood's Fourth Estate" 1960 December 25, 1961 January 1 (Reel 35-40)
- Sound recording of "Backstage on Broadway" 1960 November 13 (Reel 41-43)
- Sound recording of "Future of the Republican Party" 1960 November 27 (Reel 44-45)
- Sound recording of "Some Novelists of Our Time" 1961 January 22 (Reel 46-48)
- Sound recording of "Psyche, Psychosis and Psychiatry" 1960 December 4 (Reel 49-51)
- Sound recording of "Actor's Syndrome" 1960 December 11 (Reel 52-53)
- Sound recording of "U.N. in Crisis" 1960 November 20 (Reel 54-55)
- Sound recording of "Della Reese" n.d. (Reel 56-59)